

Mathieu Prichonnet

Eng., MBA, PMP, SAFe 5.0 Agilist

Technology | Delivery | Services | Transformation

US, Canadian, French (EU) Citizenships

Highly innovative, strategic thinker and experienced leader with over 23 years of substantial consulting and corporate experience in Portfolio, Program & Project management, Operations, Professional Services (CS), Products & ePMOs, as well as selling / implementing medium to large strategic digital life-cycle transformation initiatives at clients through the optimization of Processes, Systems, and People. Ability to simplify and de-clutter complex problems through analysis, investigation, presentation and to execute to targets / goals. High degree of collaboration with teams, at all levels, including internal / external stakeholders. Speaks French and English fluently.

■ mathieu prichonnet@yahoo.com

☐ 646-584-8331

O LUBBOCK TX USA m www.linkedin.com/in/mathieuprichonnet

BACKGROUND

Areas of Expertise:

☑ OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT (EPMO, PROF. SERVICES)

☑ STRATEGIC PLANNING & EXECUTION

☑ GLOBAL RESOURCE COORDINATION

☑ CHANGE MNGT & DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION

☑ RISK ANALYSIS & ASSESSMENT

☑ FOCUS ON CUSTOMER SUCCESS

☑ PROGRAM PORTFOLIO ROADMAPS

☑ TRAINING

DESIGN THINKING

☑ TEAM LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT DATA ANALYSIS

☑ P&L MGMT

☑ SAFE 5.0 AGILE TRANSFORMATION

☑ CLIENT RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT ☑ EPM MGMT

Selected career highlights:

✓ SUCCESSFULLY INTEGRATED MAJOR DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION CAPITAL PROJECTS (COST CONTROL) AT MAJOR UTILITY IMPACTING >2,500 EMPLOYEES ON THE DISTRIBUTION / TRANSMISSION DIVISIONS. MANAGED \$>45MM AND A TEAM OF >40+ FTE (ONSHORE / OFFSHORE) FOR OVER 2 YEARS. GENERATED OPEX SAVING IN EXCESS OF \$8M / YEAR OVER 10 YEARS.

✓ INTAKE PRIORITIZATION AND PORTFOLIO MANAGEMENT FOR A COMPANY WITH > \$150M IN ANNUAL REVENUE. LEAD DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION THROUGH SYSTEMS, PROCESSES & HUMAN CAPITAL

✓BUILD TECH STACK (OVER 10 PAAS APPLICATIONS) FOR DRONE OPERATOR TO SUPPORT GROWTH TO 500 EMPLOYEES ***********

Technical Expertise:

- End to end strategic road mapping (design thinking) for digital transformation through IoT (long-term capital spend management) for enterprise systems and centered around: (1) Systems (single source of truth), (2) Human Capital (right people / right positions), (3) Minimize Customer Data Management (analyze data), (4) Support Business Transformation (BPM & business re-engineering) / Corporate governance / Change management / create ePMOs / streamlining CAPEX & OPEX / Business Analysis / Business Case / Translate Corporate to ePMO strategies...
- Engineering Program Management and Estimation. Design and Build procurement As-a-Service / Green-Brown field Commissioning Project / Digital Twin (standardized sourcing blueprints, e-Sourcing, supplier intelligence, benchmarking and estimating, market intelligence, contracting intelligence) / GIS, T&D, Nuclear / Connected worker / Real Time Product & Project lifecycle management / Outside Plant.
- Off the shelf systems & custom application (Java, C+) Design & Implementation for Cost, Estimation, Scheduling and Transactional platforms (Oracle P6, EPPM, Unifier / Hexagon EcoSys / Clarity PM / MS Project, / InEight / Timberline / SunGard Omni & Omni trade).
- Data Migration, Conversion, and Integrations (Java / Informatica / Web methods) to ERP systems SAP PM, PS / Work Order Maximo.
- Emerging technologies (AI / Neural Network, Machine Learning, Data Science / Big Data & Data Warehouse) for intelligent analytic progress reports (Microsoft Power Business Intelligence). Custom app design and ability to collaborate with technology team to document artefacts such as deployment models, sequence Diagrams, Wireframing, as well as, working with UX/UI Designers.
- Product capability prioritization (both functional, technical and user experience), product vision and strategy, and plans for product delivery.

Verticals: Technology (Products); Telecom (Wireless/Fiber-Optic); Resources (Utilities, Chemicals, Mining, O&G); Construction / EPCs

KEY SOFT SKILLS & OTHER COMPETENCIES

Leadership (servant leader) / Strategic/ Quantitative / Problem-solving
/ Energetic / Influencer / Excellent Verbal Communication Skills &
Written Communication Skills / Analytical / Strategic thinking /
Innovation / Creative Thinking / Collaborative / Self driven /
Influencing / Motivational / Influence / Ability to prioritize
RFP, RFP, SOW / Cost Estimates / Budget / Business Case

Operations Management / Recruitment / Negotiation (Vendors) SLAs / Talent Acquisition & Hiring / Staffing / On-shore & Offshore Management / Outsourcing / Vendor Management & Contractors Performance management / Invoices / Contract Negotiation / Contract Management / Strong Organizational skills / Account Receivable

Agile Development (Scrum) / Waterfall Methodologies / Stage-gate

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DroneUp www.droneup.com

04/2022 - 04/2023

DIRECTOR DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION Lead the transformation effort to help scale business by leveraging: (PPP) Business Processes, Systems/Products and Human Capital (People) - Help educate / facilitate and drive redesign of the organizations on Processes, Systems and Products. Work through Eng., Products, Marketing, Strategy, IT, OPS, PMO, etc.

- Strategic initiatives in IOT, Multi-channel., Analytics, Gamification.
- IT OKRs / Quarterly Strategy / M&A Playbook & Integration plan.
- Mapping and System implementation for Product Engineering teams.
- Oversee Digital Strategy and Implementation of a series of multimillion dollar PPP initiatives: ERP (MS Dynamics 365), CRM (Zoho), Informative platform (Guru), PMO (Aha!, Monday & Jira/Advance Roadmaps), HRIS (Paylocity), ATS (Workable), BR Mgmt. (Jama), Infosec - RBAC/ABAC Birth Right Access, Middleware (Make).
 Portfolio \$5-10 MM

Plume www.plume.com

04/2021 - 02/2022

SENIOR MANAGER PMO PORTFOLIO Developed Intake Process & Port. Mgmt. of \$150MM revenue (KPIs + Project Control). Strategic PMO align. (Eng./Sales/Studio Dev./Support). Drive Digital Transf. (Safe5). SaaS CEM Telecom Product startup. Prosci (Change mgmt.).

Digital PXO (Freelance) <u>www.digitalpxo.com</u> 06/2020 – 04/2021

OWNER / PRODUCT MANAGER (Contract) Functional / Technical, product vision, roadmap (#1 www.digitalpxo.com – Create Website & develop strategy / #2 www.sonai- ai.com – Neuro Network & AI / #3 JEA / Florida Utility – Business alignment on processes & procedures between stakeholders (Capital Planning & Budgeting to Finance).

Accenture www.accenture.com

09/2015 - 06/2020

SENIOR MANAGER Lead partner relationship with clients in strategic initiatives for integrating mobility, web, or cloud-based enterprise solutions for various platforms to help client digitize their capital projects and manufacturing teams (cost control). Manage programs. Develop business value. Lead Onshore & Offshore teams. Architecture solution design. Budget management. Operational Performance. SLA & Licensing agreements. Cloud migration (SaaS, IaaS). Design thinking. New business: \$16MM 2019 (Lump Sum / T&M). [Projects 1-6]

One America www.oneamerica.com

02/2014 - 09/2015

PROGRAM MANAGER Lead internal Open Architecture Program of the Omni / Omni Trade platform (149k man-hours, \$25 M+). Enable current record keeping platform to handle trust product sales. Savings ≈ \$40 MM/5 years. OMNI upgrade (v5.8 to v 6.4.) Re-establish ePMO.

ABEAM www.abeam.com

03/2013 - 02/2014

SENIOR MANAGER (Contract) Forensics & Auditing advisor mandate through audit on cost management tool. Regulatory requirements - SOX reporting & compliance. Benchmarking & Data analysis on portfolio.

Hexagon www.hexagon.com

06/2007 - 03/2013

SENIOR CONSULTANT Implementation & Product SME. E2E software implementation & product / software development. Evaluate enhancements requests. (Full SDLC). [Projects 7-11]

Kiewit & Bell Mobility (EPC / Telco / Engineering) 1999 – 2007

ENGINEER / PM / MANAGER Built ePMO to manage \$40MM/Yr. (telco). Supervised \$30MM/yr. Construction & Project Controls. Estimated up to \$20 MM Project Controls. (RF / Tower / OSS/ BSS, Fiber-Optic, Civil & Electrical / JV / Lump Sum / T&M)

PRODUCT / SAAS / INFRA

Application / Platforms

Database MS ACCESS / ENT. ARCH

CLARITY PPM / ECOSYS /

Analytics TABLEAU / SOLVER / XCL

ORACLE (P6) EPPM & UNIFIER / MS PROJECT / SAP PM&PS / MAXIMO / JAMA / JIRA & CONFLUENCE / SMARTSHEETS / TIMBERLINE / AUTOCAD / IBM RATIONAL (DOORS) / PROSCI

 $\textbf{Testing/QA} \ \texttt{JIRA} \ \texttt{ZEPHIR} \ / \ \texttt{LOADRUNNER} \ / \ \texttt{HP} \ \texttt{ALM} \ \& \ \texttt{UFT} \ (\texttt{QC})$

Other VISIO / MURAL / NIST / SOX Cloud / Infra AWS / GCP

PROJECTS

- OG&E Lead proposal to implement replacement of their antiquated ArcFM VB dB to a multi-mode one (ArangoDB) and linking to both their internal Estimation and PPM platforms.
- Meta / Facebook Develop project plan for Deployment/Construction of Data Center to client specifications.
- OG&E Lead consulting management deal for EcoSys (v8.3) cost management and SAP-PS/PM custom integration enhancements (Agile method). Developed 3 yr. strategic IT PMO Business process management (tool adoption as well as strategic planning & estimating, scheduling, budgeting). Savings ≈ \$800K / yr.
- Olin Delivering execution on business requirement & functional solutioning between Primavera P6 Cloud (v15.2) and SAP-PS/PM to P6 API integrations. Reduced project delays by 7-10% (≈ \$20K/month).
- Freeport-McMoran Turn-around initiative for Application Lifecycle Management (APM) specifications at client to implement configurations on existing EcoSys (v7.4) cost management system as well as all training material (Skillshare & Litmos). Mitigate cost overrun and liabilities.
- 6. Duke Energy Technical Management (40+ FTE onshore/offshore, 4 PMs, 2yrs, \$45MM) for Transmission & Distribution team on integrated project controls implementation (Transmission). Implementation of Oracle EPPM (v15.1.2), EcoSys (v7.04) software, custom project ideation web-based application (Java) & API integration with Maximo WO order entry, Power Plan, 100 interfaces (Informatica, Web methods, Java). Testing (Product, Integration, UAT, End to End) / Migration. Cloud migration. ROI ≈ \$8MM/5 yrs.
- 7. **Federal Aviation Administration (FAA)**. Managed PMO Project Controls (P6 v6.2) & Cost analysis (EPC v6) for TAMR Ph1 (>\$250MM/yr.)
- Constellation Energy Group (CENG). Portfolio management of \$150MM/yr. for nuclear sites. Saved ≈15% CAPEX/project turnaround increase ≈10%.
- Amtrak Technical Design of Enterprise Systems & Integrations (P6 v6.2, Timberline, 10 Java interfaces)
- New York City School Construction Authority Sr. BA Oracle P6 implementation
- 11. SunTrust Bank EcoSys Implementation for Portfolio \$100MM/yr.

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University, Rawls Business School – Master's in business administration (MBA) USA (2020)

Université de Montréal, HEC Business School – Graduate degree in Operations Management Canada (2007)

Université du Québec, École de Technologie Supérieure – Construction Engineering Canada (1999)

College André-Grasset – Technical degree in Construction Estimation Canada (1995)